keepthetailwagging.com 2019-06-29

# Keep the Tail Wagging® LLC Privacy Policy | Keep the Tail Wagging

## **PRIVACY STATEMENT**

Your privacy is important to me. This privacy statement provides information about the personal information that Kimberly Gauthier and Keep the Tail Wagging® LLC (hereafter noted as Keep the Tail Wagging®, website, or blog) collect and how Keep the Tail Wagging® LLC uses that personal information.  This privacy statement only applies to this website.

### **Personal Information Collection**

**Information You Voluntarily Submit to this Website:**   Keep the Tail Wagging® may collect and use the following kinds of personal information: _y_ _our first and last name and your email address.   _You may voluntarily submit this information when you're leaving a comment on a blog post, contact me through the contact form on this website, or when you subscribe to the Keep the Tail Wagging® newsletter.

**Information that is Automatically Collected for this Website** : Keep the Tail Wagging® automatically collects specific information about you and the device (smartphone, computer, laptop, tablet) that you use when visiting this website.  For instance, when you visit KeepTheTailWagging.com, your IP address, operating system type, browser type, referring website, pages you viewed, the dates/times when you accessed this website are logged, and links you've clicked.  The purpose of this is to help me create better content to help my readers.

**Cookies** : Keep the Tail Wagging® may gather information using Session Cookies or Persistent Cookies, which are small data files stored on your browser by this website. Session Cookies expire when you close your browser while Persistent Cookies remain on your browser until you delete them by clearing your history/cookies.  These cookies aid in providing a more personalized experience on this website.

### **Use of Personal Information**

The following is a list of examples of how the website, Keep the Tail Wagging®, may use your personal information (as discussed above).

  * To operate and maintain this website, plan and update content, and plan and update products (i.e., books, ebooks, marketing materials).
  * To send you monthly and bi-monthly newsletters or email updates, which include the ability to opt-out of future correspondence (look for the “unsubscribe” link at the bottom of the email).
  * To respond to blog comments and queries submitted through the contact form on this website.
  * To track and measure advertising and user behavior (blogs read, links clicked) on this website.
  * To protect this website and website's readers from unauthorized or illegal activity (e.g., phishing, spamming).

### **Disclosure of Personal Information**

Keep the Tail Wagging® may share your information with third parties when you explicitly authorize us to share your information.

Additionally, this website partners with third-party service providers to aid in the management of various aspects of this website.  Each third-party provider's use of personal information is explained by their individual privacy policies.

Keep the Tail Wagging® currently retains the services of the following providers:

**Google Analytics** – this service tracks this website's visits and provides me with information about how you found my website, what blog post or page you visit, and how long you remain on this website.  Google Analytics may capture your IP address.  No additional personal data is obtained by Google Analytics.  You can learn more about Google's privacy policy by visiting their website: <https://policies.google.com/privacy>

**Clicky** – this service also tracks this website's visits and provides me with information about how you found my website, what blog post or page you visit, and how long you remain on this website.  Clicky may capture your IP address.  No additional personal data is obtained by Clicky.  You can learn more about Clicky's privacy policy by visiting their website: <https://clicky.com/terms>

**MailChimp** – this service is used for delivery of email updates and newsletters. When you subscribe to the newsletter, your name and email address are stored on the MailChimp servers to assist in the delivery the monthly or bi-monthly email updates and newsletters. You can learn more about MailChimp's privacy policy by visiting their website: <https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/>

**SumoMe  **– this service is used to help facilitate the sharing of blog posts and pages on social media platforms and to make it easier for visitors to subscribe to the Keep the Tail Wagging® newsletter. You can learn more about SumoMe's privacy policy by visiting their website: <https://help.sumo.com/hc/en-us/articles/218958727-Privacy-Policy>

Currently, your personal information isn't being shared with any other third-party services. However, this list may be updated in the future as the owner of the website (me, Kimberly Gauthier) finds better ways to provide you with free, useful content.

Except when required by law, I will not sell, distribute, or reveal your email addresses or other personal information without your prior consent; however, I may disclose or transfer personal information collected through this website to third parties should I sell all or a portion of Keep the Tail Wagging® LLC.  This may also apply to a merger, consolidation, or purchase of all or a portion of this website's assets or it may be related to a bankruptcy or reorganization proceeding brought by or against Keep the Tail Wagging®.

### **Anonymous Data**

Occasionally, this website may provide anonymous data, which doesn't identify you alone, to outside parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.  Examples of anonymous data may include analytics, as discussed above, and information collected from cookies.

### **Publicly Visible Information**

If you leave a comment on a blog post, the name that you use will be visible. Your email address will never be available publicly.  You also have the option to add a link to your website when leaving a blog comment.  Users will see the name that you use when you leave a comment on a blog post.

At this time, Keep the Tail Wagging® does not allow you to create a user profile or link to a social media profile.

### **Cookies**

Keep the Tail Wagging® uses cookies to prevent email capturing pop-ups and welcome mats and banner ads from being shown to regular visitors. Cookies may also be used by third-party services (listed above), such as Google Analytics and Clicky.

Users may, at any time, prevent the setting of cookies, by the Website, by using a corresponding setting of your internet browser and may thus permanently deny the setting of cookies. Furthermore, already set cookies may be deleted at any time via an Internet browser or other software programs. This is possible in all popular Internet browsers. However, if users deactivate the setting of cookies in your Internet browser, not all functions of our Website may be entirely usable.

### **Advertising**

**Display Ads**

Keep the Tail Wagging® uses a third-party advertising company to serve advertisements when you visit this website.  This service may use cookies, as explained above, to better target ads based on your preferences.

**Retargeting  Ads**

Occasionally, Keep the Tail Wagging® works with third-party companies, such as Facebook and Instagram, to market this website through advertisements on their platforms; you may see these as “Sponsored” posts in your newsfeed.  These companies may use cookies to serve ads on their platform based on someone's history of visits to this website.

**Affiliate Program Participation**

Keep the Tail Wagging® engages in affiliate marketing and may earn a commission should you click on an affiliate link and make a purchase.  These affiliate partners may engage a cookie in your browser to track sales after you click on a link.  Please note that these cookies have a limited life and do expire.

Kimberly Gauthier (owner) is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and linking to Amazon.com. Kimberly is also a member of the following affiliate advertising programs: Share-a-Sale (Raw Paws Pet Food), PawStruck.com, FullBucketHealth.com, Herbsmith Inc., In Clover, Ewegurt, and Pets Best Pet Insurance. I also have a relationship with Darwin’s Natural Pet Products as a customer and occasional freelance writer; I do not receive free raw dog food as part of this relationship.

**Newsletters**

You may choose to subscribe to a monthly or bi-monthly (schedule is subject to change) newsletter and email updates which may be used for advertising products or services used by me (owner) when raising raw fed dogs.  Newsletters sent to you may include affiliate links (discussed above) that are used to track sales.  These newsletters may also contain tracking pixels which serve to inform me of how many people open and engage (click links) with my newsletter.  The purpose of this is to help me provide better content that is useful to my readers.  What I learn is not shared by third parties.

### **Your Rights Related to Your Personal Information**

**Opt-out** – You are welcome to opt-out of all future email communications by clicking on the unsubscribe link at the bottom of newsletters and email updates.  You may also contact me (owner) at kimberly@keepthetailwagging.com to request that I remove you from the mailing list.

**Access** – If you can't recall if you have subscribed for future updates, you may contact me (owner) at kimberly@keepthetailwagging.com, and I will confirm your subscription status.

**Amend** – You may contact me (owner) at kimberly@keepthetailwagging.com to amend or update your personal information (name and email address).

**Delete** – There may come a time when you will like me to remove you from the email list (see “opt-out” above) or delete a comment on a blog post.  To do so, please contact me (owner) at kimberly@keepthetailwagging.com.

Please note that there may come a time when I may need to retain certain information for recordkeeping purposes or to complete transactions, or when required by law.

### **Sensitive Personal Information**

Please note that you should not submit sensitive personal information to this website, either in blog comments or in an email to me.  Please note that although your email address isn't visible to others (outside of myself), your comments will be visible to anyone who reads the comment thread.

If you don't want strangers to have access to information, do not post it in a blog comment on this website.

### **Children's Information**

Keep the Tail Wagging® does not knowingly collect any personal information from children under the age of 16.  If you are a parent or legal guardian of a child under the age of 16 and you believe your child has subscribed to the blog's newsletter or the child has shared personal information in a blog comment, please contact me (owner) immediately at kimberly@keepthetailwagging.com so that I may remove the information from my records.

### **Updating this Statement**

Keep the Tail Wagging® may update this privacy policy by posting a new version on this website.  With each update, this page will be shared on social media to keep you informed of changes.

**Last Update: May 4, 2018**

### **Contact Information**

If you have any questions about this privacy policy or Kimberly Gauthier’s treatment of your personal information, please write:

  * Kimberly Gauthier
  * E | [kimberly@keepthetailwagging.com](https://www.keepthetailwagging.com/contact-kimberly/ "Contact Kimberly")
